# **Robin Whittleton**

The White House, Station Row, Shalford, Surrey. GU4 8BY

PHONE: 07855 378784

EMAIL: robin@reala.net

NATIONALITY: British

## **Personal statement**

Over the last ten years of my career I have honed my skills in front-end web development in a series of design-led web agencies. I am a conscientious worker, an excellent communicator and I always endeavour to build customer requirements to the highest standard possible. I have a constant desire to improve and expand my skills with new technology and methodologies. At this point in my career I would like to use these skills to help build sites that meaningfully make peoples' lives better.

## **Employment**

### **Kyan** - Senior Web Developer

MARCH 2008 - PRESENT

- Development of a wide range of web sites and applications for startups and established businesses
- Project scoping and management with clients, to bring their systems in on time and in budget
- Close collaboration with designers to realise their layouts in a way that is accurate to their intentions across a range of devices
- Responsibility for building the entire user interface of the site, including user interaction, performance and accessibility
- Laying the foundations of an efficient back-end implementation by building skeleton applications ready for business logic
- · Mentoring of interns and providing in-office training in my specialisms

### Abacus eMedia - Senior Web Developer

AUGUST 2005 - MARCH 2008

- Development of large county council and publishing sites
- Direct management and training of a team of developers
- Training clients in both development techniques and the use of our CMS software
- Extensive experience with developing to strict government accessibility requirements

#### **Hemscott Group - Web Developer**

SEPTEMBER 2004 - AUGUST 2005

- · Styling and integration of investor relations tools
- Working with large companies (including FTSE 100s) to exact specifications

#### Freelance - Web Developer

AUGUST 2003 - AUGUST 2004

## **Skills**

#### Core

- Fluent in the core web technologies used to build responsive and semantic web sites and applications
- Use of Javascript from progressive enhancement through to custom canvas animation and frontend applications
- In-depth knowledge of cross-browser compatibility issues and the use of technologies that might cause them to arise
- Use of back-end technologies (especially Ruby on Rails) to create views and to manage asset build chains of 'compile-to' technologies (e.g. SASS)
- Preference for OS X (or other UNIX) environments

#### **Tuition**

- Mentoring of junior front-end developers to give them a more fundamental understanding of the techniques they are learning
- Presenting technologies in an interesting and understandable way, both as a conference speaker and in internal briefings

#### **Other**

- Proof-reading and copy editing, with an emphasis on readable typography
- Full clean driving licence

## **Education**

### **University of Exeter - BSc Computer Science 2:2 Honours**

SEPTEMBER 2000 - JUNE 2003

### Farnham College, Farnham, Surrey – A-levels

SEPTEMBER 1996 - JUNE 1998

A-levels in Maths (B), Physics (C). AS-levels in Music (B), Further Maths (D)

## Frensham Heights, Rowledge, Surrey - GCSEs

SEPTEMBER 1992 - JUNE 1996

10 GCSEs (A grade average) including Maths (A\*), German (A\*), Art (A), Sciences (double A), French (A)

## **Recent portfolio**

Please visit www.reala.net for examples of recent work.

## References

References supplied upon request.